THEO MORGAN

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

LANGUAGES

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, GraphQL

BACK-END

Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Loopback.io, Laraval, Symfony

FRONT-END

React, Angular, Vue, Next.js, Gatsby, Vuetify, Nuxt.js, Tailwind CSS, jQuery, SCSS

OTHER

- Agile (Scrum/Kanban)
- AWS
- GCP
- Docker
- · Kubernets, CI/CD

CONTACT

Ontario, Canada the.theomorgan88@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/morgantheo

SUMMARY

A seasoned professional web developer with real-world experience creating products and technology-based solutions to problems. During the last several years, I have focused on building websites and applications (front-end and back-end) using Angular, React, Vue and Node.js. I have worked on SaaS/CRM/SPA/eCommerce/FinTech apps, webservices, RESTful-APIs and responsive UI/UX. My major strength is that I rapidly get up to speed with the existing built-in code base/project and develop new features according to best practices but always keep an eye on the client's needs.

EDUCATION HISTORY

University of Toronto

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science | 2007 – 2012

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Self-Employed, Toronto, Canada | | Mar 2019 – Present

- Worked on a big data analytics dashboard platform that visualizes and analyzes large amounts of Big data in a short time using Vue.js and Laravel
- Frontend project structure analysis and development using React with high quality design pattern and performance on the real-time web and native apps, which includes Medical, Chatting Apps
- Migrated from Redux state management system to the combination of Apollo & React context API
- Integrated Elasticsearch with the existing MySQL for better database handling and performant querying
- Developed an internal application using Vue/Nuxt.js, Tailwind CSS and PHP, Laravel for Relationship Mangers

Technologies: React, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, , Laravel, Node.js, Apollo GraphQL, Context API, Redux

THEO MORGAN

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT

Ontario, Canada the.theomorgan88@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/morgantheo

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

OrNsoft, St.-Maurice, Île-de-France, France | Dec 2015 - Feb 2019

- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using React, Redux, HTML, CSS(Sass), flex, Babel, Sagas
- Created a React front-end admin dashboard for complex table data visualization with user-friendly search features
- Built real-time trading UI with high performance using modern socket-cluster technology
- Developed price analysis platform depend on Price api and Google Merchant api with Angular and Node
- Developed a custom eCommerce website that worked as a shop, taking all products from advertisers based on Laravel

Technologies: React, Redux, Angular, Vue.js, Laravel, Google Merchant API

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

LaCie, Paris, Île-de-France, France | Sep 2013 – Nov 2015

- Used Node.js modules like grunt, bower to integrate with designs and requirements and to interact with the databases
- Created web-based calculators using PHP, jQuery, and Ajax to show return on investment and savings
- Developed Front-end UI using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Used JavaScript and jQuery for building several functionalities of the application

Technologies: Node.js, SQL/NoSQL DB, PHP, jQuery, Ajax